Madhumathi S

Software Development Engineer

Professional Summary & Career Objective

A passionate software developer with about 2 years of experience in developing different applications. Able to take client requirements and convert them into feasible ones. Currently looking to be part of a global organization that provides the right blend of exposure, opportunities and the tech stack to grow in a company environment.

Professional Experience

Software Development Engineer 1

Dec 2018 to Oct 2019

Sysvine Technology - Chennai

- Collaborating with the team on complete application development from analysis to production migration and support.
- Adhered to best practices and standards for accessibility and cross-browser compatibility.
- Conducting website performance optimization and SEO improvements.
- Extensively used JQuery selectors in accessing various parts of the DOM and worked with AJAX.
- Developed REST API for multiple real-time projects using PHP.
- Following Agile software development principles.
- Unit testing using Jasmine.

PHP Developer

May 2017 to Jun 2018

Zenstill Analytics – Chennai

- Coding and implementing features and functionalities as per requirements.
- Maintain and improve the website by developing new user-facing and mobile-based features.
- Bug fixing and performance enhancements.
- Implementing responsive design and cross-browser compatibility.

Skills

- Programming Language: HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP,ES6,ES7,ES8
- Front-end Library: React.js, JQuery, Typescript
- Back-end Framework: Node.js
- Database: MySQL
- Helpers: Bootstrap, CSS Media Queries
- Data Representation: JSON, XML
- Code Repository: GitHub
- Code Inspection: SonarQube
- Project Methodologies: Scrum, Agile

Educational Qualification and Other details

- Bachelor in Computer science Engineering (2011-2015)
 SKP Engineering College, Tiruvannamalai
- Languages: English, Tamil
- Locality: Chennai, Tamil Nadu.